# **Mario Saul**

Software Engineer & Full Stack Web Developer

LinkedIn | 054-351-6690 | mariosaul.com | mariiosaul@gmail.com | Tel Aviv

## SUMMARY

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with 5+ years of experience in building user-centric, high-impact products for leading companies in different fields. The multi-faceted nature of developing software and the drive to always learn something new is what excites me most about being a Software Engineer.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Node.js, React, Vue.js, Html, CSS, JavaScript, Webpack, GraphQL, Swift (iOS), Kinesis, SQL, NoSQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Git, CI/CD, Docker, K8s, AWS, Heroku, Unit/Integration/E2E Testing, Web Performance, REST, OOP, Scrum.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2020 - 2021

Israel

# R&D Team Leader IMGN Media (Warner Music Group)

- Led 2 engineering teams guiding them through technical challenges to build real time, big data applications in a distributed environment that reaches millions of people
- Reshaped the development process and quality standards to improve the teams collaborations and efficiency
- Architected a scalable and robust cloud based infrastructure to process, store and present streamed live events
- Improved browser compatibility and core web vitals performance leading to big enhancement in UX and revenue

2017 - 2019

Uruguay

## Full-Stack Web Developer

**WyeWorks** 

Proiects:

#### Illume Health

- Led a 4 people team on end-to-end feature development, from product design, coding and deployment
  The RealReal
- Created a shipping microservice that significantly improved performance and resulted in major revenue savings playing a key role in the company's IPO
- Implemented algorithm to prevent the international shipment of restricted goods
- Built a gamification system to drive engagement and influence business results
- Integrated Vue.js with our existing Rails app

#### **Emeritus**

- Fully integrated new authentication system in Rails with existing SalesForce platform
- Implemented an Identity Provider (server side of SAML) for SSO authentication

2016 - 2017

Uruguay

## Full-Stack Mobile Developer Rootstrap

- Created an iMessages extension to send stickers, media files, and interactive messages
- Built a location based social chat application using PostGIS and WebSockets
- Participated in the development of an open source iOS project

#### **EDUCATION**

2013 - 2019

Uruguay

# Bsc in Software Engineer Facultad de Ingeniería de la Universidad de la República

High Honors: Ranked in the top 5%

Thesis: Designed an ETL system integrating data from heterogeneous sources to build a web platform that enables university teachers to collect, analyse, predict and report students data using machine learning techniques

### LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native | English: Proficient | Hebrew: Advanced